Guide to the Walter Metzger American Association of University Professors Records of Academic Freedom and Tenure, 1888-2009 MS2369
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Drafts and Published Materials, 1915-2006; Series 3
  - Reviews and Speeches, 1950-2000; Series 3 Subseries 2
    - Speeches: History and Social Science, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Speeches: History and Social Science, 1978; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Professional Communities, 1995-1996; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Speeches: Professional Expansion, 1982-1987; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Speech: Protest on Campus, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Brief Responses on Receipt of Awards, 1990-1991; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Speech on Youth Culture, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Speech: Teenagers and Civil Liberties, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Speech: Tenure in Hard Times, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Speech: Tenure in Hard Times, 1980-1984; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Drafts and Notes, 1915-2000; Series 3 Subseries 3
    This subseries contains drafts of book chapters, notes on manuscripts, bibliographies and footnotes, and reference materials created and used by Walter Metzger. The files are dated from 1915-2000.
    - Report- NEH Site Visit to Cornell University, 1977; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Letter of Resignation- Committee A, 1991-2000; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - Analysis of Graduate Student Dissertations, 1978-1986; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Draft: Cases, Cases, Cases, undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Chapter Outlines, 1960-1979; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 3: Quality Concerns Self- Improvement, undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 4: Cattell Movement, undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 5: Academic Freedom- Ross to Fisher, 1977; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Fragment of Chapter 7, undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Fragment of Chapter 8, undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Commemoration: Personal Removed, 1998; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Drafts, undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Evaluations: NEH Pilot Grants, 1969-1977; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Evaluations: NEH Fellowships, 1979-1981; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Evaluations: Danforth Liberal Arts Workshop, 1975; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Evaluations: NEH Seminar Proposal, 1989; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Evaluations: Smith College "Black Experience", 1968-1969; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Notes on Manuscript (1 of 2), undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - Notes on Manuscript (2 of 2), undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Bibliography, 1973-1979; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Notes, 1986; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Footnotes, undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Possible Preface Quotations, undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Draft: Chapter on Profession on Expansion (1 of 3), undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Draft: Chapter on Profession and Expansion (2 of 3), undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Draft: Chapter on Profession and Expansion (3 of 3), undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Quo Vadis, undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Report: Unfinished, Chakranarthy (Miller), 1998; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Consultant Stevens Institute of Technology, 1996-1997; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Committee A- 27th Anniversary, 1985; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Soldo, 1975-1977; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Report For Faculty Political Science, undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Report on Aging (Etzioni), February 25, 1975; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - Basr Report, January 12, 1971; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - Faculty Report: The Salary Issue, 1970-1971; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 56, Folder 11)
    - Report: Sagamon State- Due Process in Tenure Case, 1977; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 56, Folder 12)
    - Report on Yeshiva University, 1976-1977; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Report: Kramer Case, 1986-1987; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Report: Soldo Grievance Case, 1976; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Report: Formats of Teaching- Meyerson Committee, 1970; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Report: George Washington- Reichard, September 1962; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Draft: Self- Defense, undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Notes: Chapter 5- Self Definition, undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Notes: Chapter 3- Self Governance, 1915-1917; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Draft: Self Government, undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - Draft: Self Improvement, undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Loya's Survey, 1980-1982; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Teachers' Loyalty Oath, 1936; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Text and Footnotes: "1940 Statement" Law and Contemporary Problems, 1991; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Draft: "Utah: The First Investigation", undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Salaries in Higher Education (1 of 2), 1946-1958; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Salaries in Higher Education (2 of 2), 1947-1958; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Research Notes (1 of 2), 1951-1961; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Research Notes (2 of 2), 1915-1943; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Grounds for Dismissal, Due Process, and Termination, 1961-1963; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Resignation, Notes, and Other Questions, undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - AAUP Notes, undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Amy and Chapter 2 Notes, undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Dialogues, undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 58, Folder 8)
- Higher Education and Professionalism, 1939-2007; Series 4; This series is arranged by subject.
  This series contains materials that cover a range of topics within higher education and the standards of professionalism in higher learning institutions, both internationally and domestically. Materials cover the AAUP's perspective on Affirmative Action, accreditation, diversity, financial exigency, and profiles on institution types. The files are dated from 1939- 2007.
  - Faculty Compensation- Historical, 1971-1985; Series 4 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Faculty Compensation: Current, 1980-1990; Series 4 (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Current Employment Trends of Prospects, 1976-1991; Series 4 (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Academic Economy- General (1 of 2), 1968-1990; Series 4 (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Academic Economy- General (2 of 2), 1971-1992; Series 4 (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Choice of Academic Career, 1971-1989; Series 4 (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - Academic Appointment Method Standards, 1968-1980; Series 4 (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - Status of Academics, 1979-1989; Series 4 (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - Academic Marketplace, 1969-1996; Series 4 (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - Attitudes Toward Work, 1970-1973; Series 4 (Box 60, Folder 10)
  - Academic Profession- General, 1970-1999; Series 4 (Box 60, Folder 11)
  - Two Professions- Haskell, 1993-1996; Series 4 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Structure of Academic Profession, undated; Series 4 (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Structure of Academic Profession, 1992-1998; Series 4 (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Faculty Profession: Disciplinary Profession, undated; Series 4 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Research on U.S. Professoriate Academetrics, 1970-1986; Series 4 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Educational Research, 1987-1991; Series 4 (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - Professional Expansion, 1975-1986; Series 4 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - The Academic Boom, 1967-1970; Series 4 (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - The Academic Bust, 1971-1987; Series 4 (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Student Substance Abuse, May- June 1992; Series 4 (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Academic Student- Current Surveys, January 22, 1992; Series 4 (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - Academic Students: History, 1959-1991; Series 4 (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Athletics in Academe, October 3, 1990; Series 4 (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Student Grading, March 6, 2006; Series 4 (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - AAUP Policy: Accredidation, 1941-1969; Series 4 (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - Accredidation, 1958-1991; Series 4 (Box 62, Folder 10)
  - Quality Ranking of Colleges and University, 1973-1995; Series 4 (Box 62, Folder 11)
  - Multiversity, 1965-1979; Series 4 (Box 62, Folder 12)
  - C.C.N.Y- CUNY, 1965-1974; Series 4 (Box 62, Folder 13)
  - SAT Tests, 1998-2007; Series 4 (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Affirmative Action- The Law, 1996-2007; Series 4 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Affirmative Action: Higher Education, 1971-1997; Series 4 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Affirmative Action: Higher Education, 1972-1995; Series 4 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Bakke- Affirmative Action- Notes, 1978-1980; Series 4 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Multiculturalism, 1994; Series 4 (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Blacks in Academe, 1986-2006; Series 4 (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - Jewish Academics, 1994; Series 4 (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - Tenure in Great Britain, 1981-1983; Series 4 (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Clippings: British Universities, 1988-2003; Series 4 (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Clippings: British Universities, 1977-1991; Series 4 (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Open Admissions, 1970-1978; Series 4 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    General
    Folder contains information on Universities, Tenure, Academic Freedom, and Governance in Great Britain.
  - Academic Students: SAT, 1979-1995; Series 4 (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Notes For Interviews, undated; Series 4 (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Britain: Correspondence, 1988-1990; Series 4 (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Organized Notes, undated; Series 4 (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Notes For Book Review, 1993-1994; Series 4 (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Bennington, 1993-1997; Series 4 (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - General Education: The Humanities and Multicultural Curriculum, 1985-1997; Series 4 (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - General Education: The Humanities and Multicultural Curriculum, 1958-1992; Series 4 (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - Distanced Learning, 1969-1998; Series 4 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    Folder contains information on Curriculum.
  - Report on Undergraduate Curriculum, 1983-1989; Series 4 (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Deconstruction, 1990-1995; Series 4 (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Carnegie Commission Studies, 1973-1996; Series 4 (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - Recent Reforms of College Curriculum- Debate and Report, 1978-1988; Series 4 (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - Science Education, 1987-1998; Series 4 (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - Cyberspace Universities, 1995-1998; Series 4 (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - College Athletics, 2001; Series 4 (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - Academic Research Disciplines, 1972-1991; Series 4 (Box 66, Folder 9)
    Folder contains information on Faculty Attitudes.
  - Politics of Academics Surveys of Attitudes, 1975-2006; Series 4 (Box 66, Folder 10)
  - History of Federal Academic Relations, 1962-1984; Series 4 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    Folder contains information on Federal Government and Universities.
  - Federal Academic Relations- Current, 1967-2012; Series 4 (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - History of Education (U.S), 1975; Series 4 (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Financial Exigency and Law, 1977-1978; Series 4 (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Financial Exigency (1 of 2), 1974-1993; Series 4 (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Financial Exigency (2 of 2), 1974-1987; Series 4 (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Institutional Policies (1 of 2), 1974-1982; Series 4 (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Institutional Policies (2 of 2), 1965-1983; Series 4 (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Analyzing Academic Budget (1 of 2), 1973-1988; Series 4 (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - Analyzing Academic Budget (2 of 2), 1973-1981; Series 4 (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - History of RIR4C (1 of 2), 1974-1982; Series 4 (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - History of RIR4C (2 of 2), 1961-1978; Series 4 (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Committee on Faculty in Hard Times (1 of 2), 1981-1982; Series 4 (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - Committee on Faculty in Hard Times (2 of 2), 1981-1983; Series 4 (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Committee A: Processing Complaints on Gender Discrimination, 1991; Series 4 (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - AAUP Policy: Gender Discrimination, 1975-1995; Series 4 (Box 69, Folder 6)
  - Lawrence Summers and Feminist Reaction, 2005-2006; Series 4 (Box 69, Folder 7)
    Folder contains information on Gender Discrimination.
  - Institutional Types: Boston University (Silber), 1996-2003; Series 4 (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - Institutional Types: Harvard College and University, 1965-2003; Series 4 (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - Institutional Types: University of Pittsburgh, 1966-1968; Series 4 (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - Institutional Types: Hutchins at University of Chicago, 1989-1992; Series 4 (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Institutional Types: American Colleges and Universities Miscellaneous, 1976-2012; Series 4 (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - Institutional Types: Pepperdine and Other Right Wing Colleges, 1998; Series 4 (Box 70, Folder 6)
  - Institutional Types: Foundations, 1956-1986; Series 4 (Box 70, Folder 7)
  - Institutional Types: Academic Architecture, 1984; Series 4 (Box 70, Folder 8)
  - Institutional Types: Graduate Schools and Graduate Education, 1969-1993; Series 4 (Box 70, Folder 9)
  - Institutional Types: Professional Schools, 1980-1985; Series 4 (Box 70, Folder 10)
  - Institutional Types: Community Colleges, 1960-1981; Series 4 (Box 70, Folder 11)
  - Institutional Types: Women's Colleges- Coeducation, 1969-1984; Series 4 (Box 70, Folder 12)
  - Institutional Types: Black Colleges, 1964-1971; Series 4 (Box 70, Folder 13)
  - Institutional Types: Business Schools in Academe, 1986-1989; Series 4 (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - Weimar and Nazi Professoriate: Cultural Migration, 1975-1987; Series 4 (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - Article on Foreign Universities, 1968-1989; Series 4 (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - Religious Freedom and U.S. Constitution, 1993-1997; Series 4 (Box 71, Folder 4)
    Folder contains information on Religious Colleges.
  - Diversification (Bellagio), undated; Series 4 (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - Bellagio and Secularism, undated; Series 4 (Box 71, Folder 6)
  - Specialization, undated; Series 4 (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - Religious Limitations Clauses (1 of 3), 1966-1997; Series 4 (Box 72, Folder 1)
  - Religious Limitations Clauses (2 of 3), 1985-1996; Series 4 (Box 72, Folder 2)
  - Religious Limitations Clauses (3 of 3), 1966-2000; Series 4 (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - Catholic Higher Education and Academic Freedom (1 of 2), 1939-1990; Series 4 (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - Catholic Higher Education and Academic Freedom (2 of 2), 1954-1999; Series 4 (Box 72, Folder 5)
  - Protestant Higher Education, 1962-1987; Series 4 (Box 72, Folder 6)
  - Catholic Colleges and the Abortion Issue, 1985-1986; Series 4 (Box 73, Box 1)
  - List of Religious College Cases Published in Academe, undated; Series 4 (Box 73, Folder 2)
    Folder contains information on published cases associated with religious colleges.
  - Albertus Magnus College, undated; Series 4 (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - Alvernia and De Santis, 1989-1991; Series 4 (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - Bishop College- Milne, 1969; Series 4 (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - Brigham Young- Houston, 1997; Series 4 (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - Catholic University of Puerto Rico- Quilichin, 1987-1991; Series 4 (Box 73, Folder 7)
  - Columbia College- Wickersham, 1971; Series 4 (Box 73, Folder 8)
  - Columbia Union- Lindsjo, 1964-1965; Series 4 (Box 73, Folder 9)
  - Concordia Theological Seminary- Missouri, Ehlen, 1975-1999; Series 4 (Box 73, Folder 10)
  - Concordia Theological Seminary- Schmidt, 1989; Series 4 (Box 73, Folder 11)
  - Detroit- Mercy: Financial Exigency, 1978; Series 4 (Box 73, Folder 12)
  - Gonzago- Tench, 1964-1965; Series 4 (Box 73, Folder 13)
  - Grove College- Gara, 1963; Series 4 (Box 73, Folder 14)
  - Houston Baptist- Talley, 1975; Series 4 (Box 73, Folder 15)
  - University of Judaism- Falk, 1988-1995; Series 4 (Box 73, Folder 16)
  - King College- Marshall, 1974; Series 4 (Box 73, Folder 17)
  - King College- Assur, 1990-1991; Series 4 (Box 73, Folder 18)
  - Marquette- Quesnell, 1973-1997; Series 4 (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - Mercy- Shelton, 1963; Series 4 (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - Nyack- Hagen, 1994; Series 4 (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - Princeton Theological Seminary- Theron, 1959; Series 4 (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - St. Bonaventure- Warzala, 1995-1996; Series 4 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    Folder contains information on published cases associated with religious colleges and financial exigency.
  - St. Johns- O'Reilly, undated; Series 4 (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - St. Leo College, 1989-1999; Series 4 (Box 74, Folder 7)
    Folder contains information on published cases associated with religious colleges and due process.
  - St. Louis- Fleisher, 1956-1997; Series 4 (Box 74, Folder 8)
  - St. Mary's (California)- Bernando, 1976; Series 4 (Box 74, Folder 9)
  - St. Mary's (Minnesota)- Caldwell, 1968-1985; Series 4 (Box 74, Folder 10)
  - St. Meinrad- McEnroy, 1996-1997; Series 4 (Box 74, Folder 11)
  - Seton Hall- Volenski, 1986; Series 4 (Box 74, Folder 12)
  - Southeastern Baptist Theological Seminary- Mahan, 1987-1997; Series 4 (Box 74, Folder 13)
  - Southern Mazapene University, 1986; Series 4 (Box 74, Folder 14)
  - Southwestern Adventist (Texas)- Barry, 1985; Series 4 (Box 74, Folder 15)
  - Tennessee Wesleyan- Bishop, 1971-1986; Series 4 (Box 74, Folder 16)
  - Wesley College- Johnson, 1992-1997; Series 4 (Box 74, Folder 17)
  - Westminster- Gifford, 1984-1985; Series 4 (Box 74, Folder 18)
  - Catholic University- Curran: AAUP Report, 1961-1991; Series 4 (Box 74, Folder 19)
  - Curran, 1987-1990; Series 4 (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - Documents- Curran Case, November 17, 1988; Series 4 (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - Catholic University of America vs. Reverend Curran, 1988; Series 4 (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - Catholic University of America vs. Reverend Curran and Julia Fleming, undated; Series 4 (Box 75, Folder 4)
  - Curran Case, undated; Series 4 (Box 75, Folder 5)
  - Affidavit: Curran Case, 1988; Series 4 (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Affidavit: Committee A, undated; Series 4 (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - Catholic University and Curran Case (1 of 2), 1986-1988; Series 4 (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Catholic University and Curran Case (2 of 2), 1969-1988; Series 4 (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - Bibliography and Footnotes: Bellagio, undated; Series 4 (Box 76, Folder 5)
    Folder contains information on the Curran case.
  - U.S. Private Schools and Public Schools (pre-college), 2004; Series 4 (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - History of U.S. College and University: General, 1939-1991; Series 4 (Box 76, Folder 7)
  - Commentary: American Universities, 1973-1989; Series 4 (Box 77, Folder 1)
    Folder contains information on the role of university lawyers.
  - Attorneys, Series 4 (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Notes on Sexual Harassment, 1982-1995; Series 4 (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - AAUP Policy: Sexual Harassment, 1991-1995; Series 4 (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - Notes on Sexual Harassment, 1992-1996; Series 4 (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - Sexual Harassment Articles, 1983-1995; Series 4 (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - Sexual Harassment: Emotional Distress, undated; Series 4 (Box 77, Folder 7)
  - Sexual Harassment and The Law, 1991-1998; Series 4 (Box 77, Folder 8)
  - New Hampshire- Silva, 1993-1995; Series 4 (Box 77, Folder 9)
    Folder contains information on sexual harassment.
  - Tufts- Janet Bauer, 1991-1992; Series 4 (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Linda Fisher, undated; Series 4 (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - Sexual Harassment: Institutional Policies, 1990-1997; Series 4 (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - Sexual Harassment Incidents, 1982-1994; Series 4 (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - AAUP Policy: Speech Codes, 1989-1994; Series 4 (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - Notes on Speech Codes, 1990; Series 4 (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Speech Codes: Articles, 1991-1998; Series 4 (Box 78, Folder 7)
  - Speech Codes and the Law (1 of 2), 1991-1994; Series 4 (Box 78, Folder 8)
  - Speech Codes and the Law (2 of 2), 1989-1992; Series 4 (Box 78, Folder 9)
  - Speech Codes: Institutional Policies, 1993; Series 4 (Box 78, Folder 10)
  - Sexual Harassment: Hate Speech- ACLU, September 10, 1992; Series 4 (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - Open Files, 1989-1991; Series 4 (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - AAUP Policy: Mandatory Councelling, 1995; Series 4 (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - Trends in Public Higher Education, 1991-1992; Series 4 (Box 79, Folder 4)
    Folder contains information on statewide systems.
  - Statewide Systems: Public Higher Education, 1968-1990; Series 4 (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - Teaching- Authority and Relationships, 1962-1976; Series 4 (Box 79, Folder 6)
  - AAUP Policy: Grading, 1970-1986; Series 4 (Box 79, Folder 7)
  - Women in Academe, 1970-1983; Series 4 (Box 79, Folder 8)
  - AAUP Policy: Women in Academe, 1970-1987; Series 4 (Box 79, Folder 9)
  - AAUP Policy: Political Correctness (1 of 2), 1988-1993; Series 4 (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - AAUP Policy: Political Correctness (2 of 2), 1991-1993; Series 4 (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - Intellectuals, 1961-1987; Series 4 (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - Anti- Intellectualism, 1959-1962; Series 4 (Box 80, Folder 4)
  - Cultural Migration, 1968-1970; Series 4 (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - The Anti- Professional Persuasion, 1981-1990; Series 4 (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - Benefits: Higher Education (1 of 3), 1959-1973; Series 4 (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - Benefits: Higher Education (2 of 3), 1963-1973; Series 4 (Box 81, Folder 2)
  - Benefits: Higher Education (3 of 3), 1977-1998; Series 4 (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - Flexner, 1974-1987; Series 4 (Box 81, Folder 4)
  - Haber's Book on Professions, undated; Series 4 (Box 81, Folder 5)
  - History of Professionalism, undated; Series 4 (Box 81, Folder 6)
  - Institutional Generations, undated; Series 4 (Box 81, Folder 7)
  - Names: Professionals, 1985-2002; Series 4 (Box 81, Folder 8)
  - Notes for Introduction- Profession, undated; Series 4 (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - Profession- General (1 of 2), undated; Series 4 (Box 82, Folder 2)
  - Profession- General (2 of 2), 1973-1979; Series 4 (Box 82, Folder 3)
  - Profession of Law, 1973-1990; Series 4 (Box 82, Folder 4)
  - Profession of Ministry, undated; Series 4 (Box 82, Folder 5)
  - Profession of Public School Teachers, 1964-1987; Series 4 (Box 82, Folder 6)
  - Quantum of Knowledge, undated; Series 4 (Box 82, Folder 7)
  - Professional Community, 1987-1995; Series 4 (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - Profession of Accountancy, 1985; Series 4 (Box 83, Folder 2)
  - Profession of Journalism, 1977-1978; Series 4 (Box 83, Folder 3)
  - Traditional Profession- Modern Profession, undated; Series 4 (Box 83, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1914-2006; Series 5
  This series contains AAUP general correspondence, Committee A correspondence, and personal correspondence of Walter Metzger. The files are dated from 1914- 2006.
  This subseries was kept in original order from the donor.
  - 1914 and 1915 Meetings, 1914-1915; Series 5 (Box 84, Folder 1)
  - Reports, 1914-1915; Series 5 (Box 84, Folder 2)
  - January 1, 1914 to August 19, 1914, Series 5 (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - June 10, 1915 to July 31, 1915, Series 5 (Box 84, Folder 4)
  - August 20, 1914 to June 9, 1915, 1914-1915; Series 5 (Box 84, Folder 5)
  - August 1, 1915 to September 30, 1915, Series 5 (Box 84, Folder 6)
  - October 1, 1915 to December 6, 1915, Series 5 (Box 84, Folder 7)